It's already too late.
Alien Resurrection is a science fiction, horror, action
film directed by Jean-Pierre Jeunet.
Two hundred years after Lt.
Ripley died, a group of scientists clone her,
hoping to breed the ultimate weapon.
But the new Ripley is full of surprises … as are the new aliens.
Ripley must team with a band of smugglers to keep
the creatures from reaching Earth.
Ripley, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Call, played by Winona Ryder.
Vriess, played by Dominique Pinon.
Johner, played by Ron Perlman.
Christie, played by Gary Dourdan.
Elgyn, played by Michael Wincott.
Alien Resurrection is a 1997 American science fiction horror film directed by Jean-Pierre
Jeunet, written by Joss Whedon, and starring Sigourney Weaver and Winona Ryder.
It is the fourth installment of the Alien franchise, and was filmed at
the 20th Century Fox studios in Los Angeles, California.
In the film, set 200 years after Alien 3 (1992), Ellen Ripley is cloned
and an Alien queen is surgically removed from her body.
The United Systems Military (USM) hopes to breed Aliens to study and research on the spaceship USM
Auriga, using human hosts abducted and delivered to them by a group of mercenaries.
The Aliens escape their enclosures, and Ripley and the mercenaries attempt
to escape and destroy the Auriga before it reaches Earth.
Additional roles are played by Ron Perlman, Dan Hedaya, J.
Freeman, Brad Dourif, and Michael Wincott.
Alien Resurrection had its premiere in Paris on November 6, 1997,
and was released to the public on November 12.
It grossed US$47.8 million in the United States and Canada, making it
the least successful of the Alien series in that market.
It grossed $161 million worldwide.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who criticized the screenplay
but praised Weaver's performance and Jeunet's direction.
The film was nominated for six Saturn Awards, including Best Science Fiction Film, Best Actress
for Weaver, Best Supporting Actress for Ryder, and Best Direction for Jeunet.
A sequel to Resurrection was planned, as Whedon had
written an earth-set script for Alien 5.
Sigourney Weaver was not interested in this setting, but has remained open to
reprising her role as Ellen Ripley on the condition that she likes the story.
More sequels were planned to follow Resurrection, but were ultimately abandoned
as the crossover series arrived with the 2004 film Alien vs.
Predator, along with the prequel series including the 2012 film Prometheus.
The storylines of Resurrection have been continued in the comic series Aliens versus Predator
versus The Terminator, and books Aliens: Original Sin and Alien: Sea of Sorrows.
The film explores themes of android, smuggling
(contraband), dystopia, mercenary, sequel.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.